♪ ♪
Laura, do you think
I like working late?
Stop lying to me, David!
It's that blonde!
Stop lying to me!
You're seeing her again!
I told you and I've
told you it's over!
You're going to see her tonight.
Laura, I'm ending this
conversation right now!
Excuse me, but Mr. Freemont's
meeting's just ending.
If you want to catch
him, it's a good time.
I didn't want to bother you.
But when this came
up on the computer,
I thought I should mention it.
No, no, you did the right thing.
This is very distressing.
Have you, uh...
mentioned this to anyone else?
Do you want me to?
Not till we sort it out.
If your computer comes
up with anything else,
just bring it to me.
What was that about?
Oh, nothing.
A very old, very
valued customer...
with a very large overdraft.
Well, this valued customer
certainly doesn't
have that problem.
The man who just came in here...
where did he go?
Sorry, ma'am... I
can't tell you that.
Where is he?
He went up to the penthouse.
You'll need my
key for the elevator.
What are you doing? I'm reaching
for the key.
Hurry up.
Easy, lady, easy.
This couldn't wait.
I had to see you.
Penthouse.
David.
Hey, Julie.
Hi... hi, Gus.
New suit.
Do you like it? Ooh, yeah.
You don't think it's too...
No, it's right on the money.
Thank you. Yeah.
I understand you've
taken on Laura McCord.
Yeah.
Interesting how
she pointed a gun
at a security
guard, and then, uh,
turned up next to the
body of her dead husband
with the gun in her hand.
She's admitted to all that.
Then, how can you
possibly think she's innocent?
There was a witness, a woman.
If I can find that witness...
Have you read
the residue report?
Well, sure.
I don't guess you would
spring for a bottle of pop.
Sure.
What do you want?
Grape.
Grape. Orange.
Orange. Fine.
Orange.
Thanks. Thank you.
The residue report
shows she had powder
all over her hand,
so she obviously fired the gun
and killed her husband.
Well, there were two
shots several seconds apart.
She shot him twice.
That doesn't make any sense.
The coroner's report said
that each shot was fatal.
Why shoot him twice?
Doesn't stand to reason.
Oh, come on, we're
not talking about reason.
We're not? No.
We're talking...
"Hell hath no fury
like a woman scorned."
Oh.
Who doesn't know that?
Laura McCord is
jealous, excitable,
high-strung, and she
can hold a grudge,
but she did not
kill her husband.
Somebody besides David
McCord and the witness
was in that apartment
when Laura arrived.
That person killed David McCord.
And when Laura
collapsed, he put the gun
in her hand, fired
a second shot.
That is some incredible story.
It is, isn't it?
Yeah.
Well, I don't buy it.
Enjoy your lunch.
Oh, I've been trying to.
Oh.
That is a nice suit.
And you are the security guard
at the Carlisle Arms?
For seven years now, yes.
Were you working the night
of David McCord's murder?
I was.
Did anything unusual
happen that night?
Yes.
A woman came in waving a gun
and demanding to know
where Mr. McCord was.
What did you do?
She had a gun on me.
I used my key
to let her upstairs.
And then what did you do?
I called the police.
And when the police arrived,
I went outside to meet them.
Uh... we heard a gunshot.
Then, we went up
to the penthouse.
And what did you
find in that penthouse?
The dead man.
And next to him was the
woman from the lobby...
with the gun in her hand.
Can you identify that woman?
Yes, I can.
Is she here in the courtroom?
She is.
Would you point her out to us?
Your Honor!
Your Honor, I want to testify.
That's the woman
I caught with David.
His mistress.
I was there.
I saw the murder.
I want to testify.
Order in the court.
Counsel, please
approach the bench.
Uh... What do you think?
I don't know.
Your Honor, the people
would like a recess
so I can interview this woman.
Your Honor, if justice
is what we're looking for,
this woman is an eyewitness.
Why don't we put
her on the stand
and hear her story?
Miss March?
Just so I understand,
you want to waive
any defense right
to a continuance
and just put this
woman on the stand?
Yeah.
Why not?
I'll give you a few
minutes to prepare.
Thank you, Your Honor.
That woman saw
everything, and she's
willing to testify.
Now, let's hear
what she has to say.
Mr. Matlock, Miss
March, may we proceed?
- Yes, Your Honor.
Bailiff, bring the witness in.
Well, bring her in.
Uh, Your Honor,
she's disappeared.
Julie! Oh.
Ben, you scared
me half to death.
What are you doing here?
Same as you, I guess.
Looking for evidence.
Are you all right?
In a minute.
Court order sealed
that elevator.
I had to walk all the
way up five or six floors.
Seven, actually.
Ooh.
What do you suppose a...
apartment like this costs?
A lot.
Ben, your jacket.
Oh... paint.
Paint on my jacket.
Julie March.
Yes.
Where?
What time was that?
Uh, well, I think
we're going to
need more than that,
but, uh, would you
keep me informed?
Thanks.
Anything?
Uh, I don't know.
The police found a cab driver
who may or may not
have picked her up.
Where did he take her?
The bus station.
No, not our witness.
I don't think the bus
station. Uh-uh, I doubt it.
Uh, why do you think a...
woman like... like that
would have, uh, hiking boots
with, uh, mud all over them?
Well, maybe...
she likes to hike.
I mean, even a woman like that
can't spend all of
her time... like that.
Ah.
Well... my turn to buy lunch.
Oh... another time.
Well... okay.
Busy.
Okay, yeah, oh, yeah.
What are you doing here?
Well,
after we left that
woman's apartment,
I got to thinking
about the red clay
you found on her shoes.
I got to wondering why a
woman with an expensive car
like that in the garage
would take a taxi.
And I talked to
that taxi driver,
and he told me that the woman
he picked up spoke with a...
Slight hill accent.
And he brought her
to the bus station.
And court reconvenes
in 48 hours,
so I have 48 hours
to find that witness.
Hi.
By any chance, do you recall
a young woman,
early 20s, very pretty,
who might have
bought a ticket, oh, say,
in the last couple of hours
to somewhere in the hills?
No.
Let's put it this way.
Where in the hills
would a person go
if a person went to the hills?
I don't know.
Gunther's Creek.
That's where the mud came
from that was on her boots
and that's where she is.
You did sell a
ticket to a pretty girl
to Gunther's Creek, didn't you?
Yeah.
I would like a
window seat, please.
I'll drive you. What?
We might get lucky.
We might find the witness
before court reconvenes.
Mrs. Morris, your husband is
waiting at Arrival Gate 50.
Right over here.
We should do this more often.
Chase a witness
back up in the hills?
No.
No, I mean, get
out of our offices.
Yeah. You know, take the time
to stop and smell the flowers.
Yeah. Yeah.
Oh, Ben, I'll get
that paint out for you.
Just give me your
jacket when we get back.
Oh, I can't give you
my clothes to clean.
You don't take in laundry.
Why not? It's just a jacket.
That's too much trouble.
Oh, not as much trouble
as driving me all the
way to Gunther's Creek.
Well, actually, I'm...
I'm doing that more for myself.
See, when we find that witness,
she'll identify David
McCord's killer.
Right. Laura McCord.
Or you mean who
framed Laura McCord.
♪ ♪
I'm going to stop and talk
to these boys for awhile.
I'll see what I can
find out in the store.
Okay.
Hey, hey, hey!
Good pickin', good pickin'.
Good pickin'. Boy!
Sure gets hot up here in Georgia
this time of year, doesn't it?
Yeah, it does. It gets hot.
Yup, yup, yup.
That's a nice guitar.
I used to, I used
to do a little pickin'.
I used to pick all the time.
I used... I used to pick
with St. Clair Bass Night.
I guess you remember
St. Clair Bass Night?
Went barefooted all the time.
Said shoes bothered his feet.
Yeah. Well, he was...
He was a great picker.
Great picker.
Oh!
♪ Well... ♪
♪ Honey, let me
be your salty dog ♪
♪ Or I won't be
your man at all ♪
♪ Honey, let me be
your salty dog... ♪
Pop the hood for me, boss.
♪ Honey, let me
be your salty dog. ♪
♪ ♪
Hey-hey-hey!
All right!
Well, I guess you
can... look at it this way,
I can only get better.
I enjoyed that. I enjoyed that.
Yes, sir!
The Georgia hills are
beautiful this time of year.
Beautiful.
I guess folks born here go away
looking for someplace
that's better,
always wind up coming back here.
Ben? Ben?
Look at this quilt. Ooh...
The workmanship
is just beautiful.
Nice. It's a wedding quilt.
Yeah...: How're you doing?
Um, I'll meet you over
at that cafe in a minute. Okay.
Yeah! Yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah...
Folks coming home for Christmas.
Folks coming home
for Thanksgiving.
Just folks... coming home.
Mister, you looking
for information?
Going to cost you
a hundred bucks.
Iced tea please, lots of lemon.
Yeah, nothing like an iced tea
on a hot day, is there? No.
Say, you're from Atlanta?
Uh, yes. How'd you know?
Well, I'm a salesman.
Farm implements.
Good salesman
learns to read people.
Oh, hey-hey-hey, no, no.
This one's on me. Oh, no, no.
No-no, look, look,
look... Hey, please.
It's just my way of
saying, "Welcome to town."
Well, thank you. Take care.
Hey. I-I got lucky.
Our mystery lady is not
Sandra Daniels, the
name on the condo...
Wanda Sutton.
The lady with the quilts told me
she saw Wanda
get off the noon bus.
She also told me
where Wanda lives,
and that her boyfriend,
Dan, lives way
back in the hills.
Oh... Say, uh,
why don't you and I
go sit in one of those
booths over there, huh?
What do you say, sweet face?
Yeah... Uh... Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey, listen!
Don't start something
you can't finish, pops!
Hey! "Pops"!
Jackass!
Touch your hair... "Pops"!
You took care of him.
Me, too. Thanks.
Dang gone... Are we out of gas?
No, we're not out of gas.
Must be the carburetor.
Oh, no.
Oh, wait...
I'll be right back.
Well, you don't have
a distributor cap.
Why not?
Somebody took it.
You know where I can get one?
Maybe.
Going to cost you a hundred.
Oh, come on! Ben, we can walk.
The lady with the quilts
said that Wanda's place
is just a mile or
two up the road.
Yeah. Yeah.
Hello! Hello!
Hello!
The name on the mailbox
says "Sutton," Yeah.
So this must be the right
place. Wait, wait, wait...
Oh! Good suit... Hello! Hello!
Hey, here, here...
Oh, great! Let's get
some of this business.
Some of this business here.
Ooh...
Oh, thank you. Mmm... Oh, good?
Oh, it's wonderful!
Matlock!
Put your hands up.
Thank you.
Oh... Ben?
Ben?
Ben? Hmm?
Were you asleep?
I can't understand a
word you're saying.
Ben, try to reach my ropes.
Oh, who were those men?
How did they know we
were looking for Wanda?
Are they looking for Wanda, too?
It doesn't make any sense.
Why did they tie us up?
I mean, why didn't
they just shoot us?
I would have. Wouldn't you?
No. No.
Oh, I can't believe
this is happening to us.
First, that long drive.
And then, that awful
man in the cafe.
And then, the distributor
cap and then we get tied up.
Oh, excuse me.
My stomach is growling.
We should have
eaten in that cafe.
Weren't you hungry?
You didn't say anything.
Well, you should've
said something.
Did you notice they had waffles?
Pancakes. Waffles.
Syrup... Waffles with apples...
Waffles with cream cheese.
Biscuits!
Potato pie.
Scallop... Oh!
Oh... I'm free.
Put your hands up.
Ben... Hmm...
Uh, this is Ben
Matlock from Atlanta.
He's a lawyer.
This is my barn and
you're trespassing.
Oh, are you Dan?
How do you know my name?
A... a lady from town
said you were a good
friend of Wanda's.
Wanda moved to Atlanta
a couple of years ago.
Yes. Yes.
That's why we're here.
I told you to put
those hands up!
I'm Julie March
and I'm a lawyer, too.
Uh, actually,
I'm with the
Atlanta D.A.'s office.
Now, I know you're just
trying to protect Wanda,
and that's wonderful, but
she's in terrible trouble.
Can I untie him?
Wanda is a witness to murder,
and she can
identify the killers.
But unfortunately,
there are some very,
very dangerous men
looking for her.
You ain't gonna hurt Wanda?
No, no, we can see
that she's protected. If
they don't get to her first.
I got Wanda where she's safe.
You can't hide her forever, Dan.
We want to help her.
Wanda.
It's me.
You brought people.
It's-it's Ben Matlock and
Julie March from court.
We want to help.
Thank you, Mr. Matlock.
You've been very helpful.
Let's go. He's waiting.
Wanda, no.
Shut up!
It's all right, Dan.
Please, they'll kill all of us.
It's all right,
I'll go with you.
Just please don't hurt them.
Drop your gun!
Don't even think of it!
No!
Stop!
Come on, let's go.
This is your fault, damn
it! You led those men here!
Stop it! It's not his fault!
Who are those men?
- They work for that guy.
- What guy?
That foreigner who built the
big house down by the lake
about three years ago.
He ruined her life.
One night, she just decided
to go to a party there.
I told her they wouldn't let
her in, but she went anyway.
The next day, she
moved to Atlanta.
We were going to be married.
Since I was eight years old,
I never loved anybody else.
Where you going?
I'm gonna circle around back.
Be careful.
Sorry, folks, the club's
closed for a private party.
Um, my name's Ben
Matlock. I'm a lawyer.
We need to see the host.
Please turn your vehicle
around. You're on private property.
I'm a deputy D.A.
Now unless your boss wants
us back here in a half hour
with a court order
and the police,
you better let us in.
Right through there.
Is that our host?
Uh..., Mr. Freemont?
Well, Mr. Matlock,
Ms. March. What a surprise
to see you, Mr. Freemont.
My wife's family has a house
on the other side of the lake.
We've summered here for years.
Are you throwing this party?
Oh, no, no, no.
I'm just here to be neighborly.
Why are you here?
Uh, uh, well,
it's... a long story.
Have a good time.
Oh, thanks.
Oh, excuse me. My wife. Okay.
Curious, isn't it?
I know.
It's Albert Agura.
Excuse me. Oh, sure.
Welcome.
Good afternoon.
Hello.
Ladies.
Look at this. Hello.
I understand you wish to see me?
Are you our host?
That's my caviar.
How can I help you?
My name's Ben
Matlock. I'm a lawyer.
This is Julie March.
She's the assistant
D.A. from Atlanta.
We're looking for a
material witness to a murder
and we have reason to believe
she was brought
here against her will.
Forced to come to my party?
And who is this rotten guest?
Wanda Sutton.
Do you know her, Mr. Agura?
Everybody that lives by the
lake knows Wanda Sutton.
Robert, have you
seen Ms. Sutton?
In the boathouse.
One of her favorite spots.
It's quite possible she would
not want to be disturbed.
Now I get it.
Agura's that foreigner
Wanda ran off with.
Yeah, yeah.
Millions, millions,
millions in drugs. Ruthless.
Wanda is his mistress
and he wanted his mistress back.
Yeah. Yeah, I guess
the Justice Department
would like to talk to Wanda
after all she's seen and heard.
Oh, that poor girl.
I bet Wanda saw
something just recently
that Mr. Agura just as
soon she not talk about.
Right there.
Bring it up a little closer.
Not a sign of them.
She can't have
disappeared into thin air.
Oh, thank you so much.
Keep searching.
Whatever it takes.
I feel terrible that
something like this
could happen to a guest of mine.
Yes, sir.
Excuse me.
Did I see you in town?
Yep.
At the store.
I do chores for Mr. Agura.
Mr. Matlock, I want to help,
but I gave you everything
David was working on
when you first came in
here right after he was shot.
I know you have, and I
appreciate it, I really do,
but humor me.
Run just one more computer check
to see where it leads,
what do you say?
All right, I'll give it a try.
Ben, Ben, are you in there?
Yeah. Yeah.
I'm just... I'm
just sitting here.
Hi.
You know, I've been thinking.
About the case?
Yeah. I wish we could
have found Wanda.
Yeah.
Do you think we should
ask for a postponement?
Um... um... Uh, no, I think...
I think I'd like to go ahead.
Why, have you
found out something?
Well, I might have.
Well, you certainly have
a lot of opportunities.
Your client certainly
could have done it.
I mean, her husband
was having an affair
and the gun was in her hand.
Yeah, the gun...
Or it could have been
either of those two guys
who worked for Agura. Yeah.
Or Agura himself.
He certainly had motive.
I mean, his girlfriend
was cheating on him
with Laura's husband.
But don't get me wrong...
I still believe Laura
McCord is guilty.
Um... You know, uh,
you know, when I, uh...
uncover something, you know,
that might be important...
A clue or some
evidence or something...
I, uh, the first
thing I think is, um,
I want to tell you.
It is?
Sometimes.
Oh, but you can't do that. No.
No, no. Ethics and all.
It's a strange life
we lead, isn't it?
Sometimes we're together,
and sometimes we're poles apart.
I know.
But we... almost got a chance
to work together this
one time, didn't we?
Yeah, trudging up those hills.
Oh, I have never been
so hungry and so dusty.
And tired.
Lost.
And footsore.
I had the time of my life.
I'll certainly never forget it.
Nor I.
Yeah?
Whichever way this
turns out, I wish...
I do, too.
Do you swear to tell
the truth, the whole truth
and nothing but the truth? I do.
Once again, you're a hell
of a driving companion.
Let's go somewhere
sometime just for fun.
Yeah, let's do, let's do. And...
If I might interrupt.
Are you prepared to
examine this witness?
Uh, yes, ma'am.
Uh, Mr. Agura, that's
an elegant home
you have out near
Gunther's Creek.
We like it.
It's nice.
And that must mean
business is good?
Indeed.
Exactly what
business are you in?
I deal in international
finance. Oh.
So you're a... an important
man, a powerful man.
I wouldn't say that.
Isn't it true though,
that you travel
in the company of
two bodyguards...
Eduardo Cortez and Frank Grady?
I employ literally
hundreds of people.
Including, uh, Eduardo
Cortez and Frank Grady.
Yes. Uh...
Uh, this is, uh,
People's Exhibit G.
This gun is owned
by the defendant.
Do you recognize
this gun, do you?
Not at all.
If, uh...
If I told you that
this gun was last
in the possession of your
employee, uh, Mr. Grady,
would that stir
your recollection?
No.
Isn't it true... that you were
at the scene of David
McCord's murder?
No, it is not true. And during
that scene, uh, the
defendant... The victim's wife,
uh, arrived, and collapsed.
And at that time, you
removed this gun from her hand
and placed the murder
weapon in her hand.
And even though the
victim was already dead,
you fired a second
shot into his body.
Leaving powder marks on her hand
to make it look as if
she were the real killer.
I did no such thing.
And then, you instructed your
employee to get rid of this gun.
And unbeknownst
to you, he kept it.
Now... before you answer,
I have to warn you.
Mr. Grady had agreed
to testify to these facts.
All right.
It's true.
But I did not kill David McCord!
No further questions.
Why did you stop?
He didn't do it.
Mr. Matlock, would
you like to reconsider?
Uh, no, ma'am.
Uh, Defense would like to call
Mr. Thomas
Freemont to the stand.
Mr. Freemont, you're president
of the Atlanta Crestmore Bank.
Isn't that right?
I am, sir, for almost...
five years now.
Yeah. And-and
w-w-what kind of shape
was the, the bank in
when you took it over?
Oh, it was a very solid,
medium-sized bank.
But you really turned
it around, didn't you?
Well... we have experienced
some growth, yes.
You're being very modest.
Your bank is one of the five
largest banks in
the city, isn't it?
One of the five
largest in the state,
as long as I'm not being modest.
Yeah.
Uh, how did you come to know,
uh, our missing
witness, Wanda Sutton?
Well, I...
I'm afraid I don't
know her at all.
Well, I...
I... well, now, I
am confused. Um...
According to these,
uh, computer... uh, runs,
you do know her.
Mr. Matlock, the witness
has already answered
your question.
Oh, I apologize, Your Honor.
I'll rephrase.
Uh, I guess you could
look at, uh, these runs
and could explain them to us.
Oh, yes. These are
some of the computerized
accounting statements for
the bank's promotion account.
Now, there is a...
there is a bill that comes up
month after month after month
in the amount of $3,280.
And it goes right into your
residential mortgage account.
Doesn't it?
Well, I see it, but I
don't know what it's for.
Those are the mortgage payments
on Wanda Sutton's condominium.
- Authorized by you.
- Your Honor?
Is Mr. Matlock sure
where he's going with this?
Mr. Matlock?
Uh... Yes.
And here is
something that's
even more fascinating.
Uh, are you aware...
that Wanda Sutton has a, uh,
credit card issued by your bank?
Well, the bank issues
thousands of credit cards.
Well, this isn't an
ordinary credit card.
This is one of those
fancy platinum credit cards.
With no credit limits.
No credit limit...
For a girl with no
apparent means of support.
And you approved...
her application, didn't you?
And arranged that the
bills be paid from the fund.
Well, maybe we better
examine these
figures. No, no, no.
That's not necessary.
I issued the card.
And the bills were
paid from the fund?
If you say so.
Hmm...
And David McCord worked
in the credit card department.
And that popped
up in his computer.
And he went over
to the condominium
you shared with your mistress.
Confronted you.
Maybe he was going
to blackmail
you... I don't know.
But that's why you killed him.
Now, wait a minute.
All right, Wanda
and I were lovers.
And perhaps, I did use funds
from the bank's
promotion account.
But that's a far cry
from killing anybody.
Yeah.
Yeah, maybe you're right.
But there is one other thing.
There is one other thing.
About a year ago, your big...
important bank was in
serious financial trouble.
You expanded too fast.
Several big loans went sour
and you needed cash bad.
The bank is one of the
strongest in the South.
Only because you made
your deal with the devil,
and you got a windfall.
Huge cash deposits.
Vast amounts of money.
$100 million in drug money
from your friend, Mr. Agura.
And then suddenly,
you were only his employee.
His slave.
You were forced to
launder drug money
month after month
after month after month.
And that's what popped up
in David McCord's computer.
And that is a federal offense
with years in prison.
And that is motive for murder.
Isn't it?
I did not kill David McCord!
I wasn't even there
the night of the murder!
Yes, you were.
I was not!
Where do you buy your suits?
Well, my...
They're custom-made
for me by my tailor.
I imagine they're
expensive. Yes, yes, they are.
What do you do with them when
you're through wearing them?
I give them to charity.
All of them?
Yes.
All... but one.
See, when...
When I went back up
to that condominium
looking for clues, I had to...
I had to go up the stairs.
And I rubbed against
the wall, and I got...
red paint on my coat.
They've been painting
that building for months.
They've been painting it
for three and a half years,
and they're still not finished.
Now, I imagine
when you went up and
down that penthouse,
you used the elevator.
But on the night
of the murder...
you used the stairs.
You used the stairs
to avoid the police.
I was not in the apartment!
And you rubbed against
the wall just like I did.
You got red paint on your suit.
And when you got home
to your house on the lake,
you threw that suit away.
Now if I threw my suit away,
I don't imagine
anybody would pick it up.
Of course, I wouldn't
throw it away.
But somebody found your suit.
An expensive pinstripe suit.
What's a little paint?
And that person
has been very proud
to wear that suit.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, right here.
Just come right
here, right here.
Here.
See right here?
Red paint.
Same shade.
This coat even has your initials
on the inside pocket.
That's your coat.
I am not answering
any more questions.
I think that's a sound move.
Your Honor, at this time
I request that all charges
against my client be dropped.
The People concur, Your Honor.
Case dismissed.
♪ ♪
Oh, here we are.
Ice cold.
How did you get
such an inspired idea?
Oh, it must be the
company I keep.
We've been looking
all over for you.
Hi.
If you want to
testify, the trial's over.
Actually, we heard you were
down here having a picnic,
so we brought you
some blueberry cobbler.
Oh! Thank you. And some news.
- We got married.
- Oh, Danny!
Hey, you know, you said
let's go somewhere for fun.
This turned out to be perfect.
Let's help ourselves.
Chicken looks mighty good.
Yes, oh, yes, help yourself.
Let me try some of that
blueberry cobbler. There you go.
www.tvsubtitles.net